let's say you have to multiply two
binomials for example x + 3 and x - 2
you multiply the first terms of each
binomial the outer terms the inner terms
and then the last terms you lastly
combine any like terms to get the final
result this is known as the foil method
and here's a visualization showing how
it works say we have a rectangle where
its area is equal to its width time its
height if the width and height are each
broken into two variables A and B and C
and D we would have to multiply these
binomials to find the area of the re
rectangle an alternative approach would
be to break the rectangle down into four
smaller rectangles it's easier to
visualize their area and we can find the
area of the total rectangle by adding up
all the smaller areas by doing so we
find the total area is equal to AC plus
a d plus BC plus BD which yields the
exact same result as if you were to
follow the foil method the same approach
can be used to visualize multiplying
larger polinomial the order in which you
add the terms doesn't matter as long as
you're multiplying every possible pair
between left and right comment your
thoughts below and subscribe for more
stem content